Now it has begun, Apkami. This time we're joined by Maria Makino from Morning Musume.24 and Riai Matsunaga from Juice Juice.
This programme goes behind the scenes of the production of various artists belonging to the upfront group.
We will bring you the process of production, including our recordings and rehearsals.
Now then, let's first go behind the scenes with the two MCs.
I'm Maria Wood and I'm going to talk about the boots I'm using on tour. I have boots that I've been using on tour for 56 years and I'm starting to feel sorry for them. But...
I'm looking for new boots now.
What kind of boots do you usually wear?
I usually wear boots with a heel that's maybe 10 centimetres high, but the toes aren't too close to the floor.
They're thick-soled, so the heel and toe aren't too rounded.
So the ideal is not too round, not too round on the toes, but something that makes your feet look nice.
Yes, I do.
So you can jump.
Preferably something light.
Let me know if you have any good ones.
I'm Matsunaga.
At the Hina Fest.
I performed Mori Musume's 'Because it's a free country
I performed
At that time
I was really surprised at how detailed the chorus was.
It was partly because there were so many choruses, but also because the rhythm of the chorus was so detailed.
But the rhythm of the chorus was very detailed.
So if the notes in my song were even a little long
I was really surprised at the detail of the song.
I was really surprised by the detail of the song and struggled with it.
It's true that the way I sing is different from the way I usually sing JuiceJuice's songs.
It's totally different, but I really enjoyed it.
I feel like I found a new challenge.
It was great.
It was really cool.
You did it! Thank you very much.
Now let's start with this up-cam, here.
Mai OZEKI, YES! Spring forecast music video making-of.
24 April release.
Here's a look at the making of the music video for Mai OZEKI's latest single, YES!
Good morning, today we are filming YES!
Music video shoot.
It's a cheerful song today.
We've got a lot of smiles on our faces and a lot of energy.
I'm going to work hard from this morning.
Collect these radios.
Connect the radios, connect the phones.
Say, "Hah!
I hear a voice from the radio on the other side.
I'm under the impression that you're like...
Anyway, in order to get along with the girl on the other side.
I'd do all sorts of things to get on with the girl on the other side.
Eventually, you get to know each other.
Open that window over there.
I was like, "Ha-ha-ha" with the girl on the other side.
It was like singing along happily, so I'll be nice.
It's not like there's ever a "hello", so yes, there's always a surprise.
Surprises are always welcome, aren't they?
I say YES!
It'll be fine tomorrow.
Almost certainly.
I say HO!
I want to be.
You'll see.
Miraculous love.
I'd like to be seen as a miracle love.
While we're talking about love, the festival is over.
Yes, and please give me the feeling that I'm sitting in a chair.
Sofa.
I said I'm going to refamis the lens here, and I'm going to mount it here, and it's going to go like this, and it's going to go like this, and it's going to go like this.
And then I'll go over to the other one and say...
It's just expensive.
I'll just laugh at it one at a time, and then I'll just laugh at it one at a time, and then I'll just laugh at it one at a time, and then I'll just laugh at it one at a time, and then I'll just laugh at it one at a time.
I'm sure you can do something if you combine the two on the radio.
To call up the girl next door.
To call the girl next to me.
To call the girl next door, so she can hear me.
Like a radio.
It's like a radio that's connected to a radio.
It seems to be a radio.
Me.
He's not listening to me at all, he's looking at the camera, which is kind of fun.
Good luck, yes, yes, yes, yes, cut.
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes.
He's so cute!
Yay!
side
And the himegao.
Yes, this is a great outfit and I'm almost finished, but here, I'm going to smile and eat a lot of food because it's my lunch break, lol.
I feel like I'm making tennis out of sadness, so I'm going to look at the front.
Let's go to the corner of the window for a minute.
And the front.
Hey, thanks for the cut, me.
me
MEME.
You're smiling a bit, but the tape's sad.
Did you get to see the camera?
Did they show you the camera?
Cut.
It's a wonderful feeling.
Oh, no.
How's it going?
Oh, that's good. Yes, cut!
Yes, we got it right!
The music video shoot for YES!
Yes, so this song is very pop and bright.
It's a song that's going to be a lot of fun at live performances.
I'm looking forward to performing it.
The music video is also very bright and cheerful.
But it has an interesting structure with one person playing two roles, so I think you can enjoy watching it over and over again.
This time, since it's the debut single of Mai OZEKI, the two songs have completely different colours, so you can enjoy both cool Mai OZEKI and cute, energetic Mai OZEKI.
I hope you can enjoy the cute and energetic OZEKI Mai.
Please continue to support us!
Bye bye!
I thought it was a very cute music video.
I think that Mai OZEKI from the perspective of a paper plane is cute, and I don't think that's easy to do.
Mai OZEKI is cute both in a cheerful and matured way.
I wanted to be her friend too.
I thought the music was really stylish.
The first thing that catches my ear is the bass line.
The combination of the guitar line, the bass line and the melody line...
The way the guitar line, bass line and melody line are combined is very stylish.
And the way Ozeki's voice is on top of it...
I don't know how to say it, but it's a great song.
I thought it was really nice!
This is the making of the music video for Maiyesu Koseki's Spring Forecast.
Let's work hard together!
Next, here it is!
A new corner, Apkami Photo Gallery!
It's a new corner starting from this time!
What kind of contents will it be?
Let's have a look.
This is Danbaralulu from JuiceJuice.
In this corner, we discuss certain topics with Hello Project members,
Let's deepen our understanding of each other and get to know the members better.
And finally, write down the words that impressed you during the talk on this board,
The aim of this corner is to write down the memorable words of the talk on this board and to capture them in a photograph to keep.
So, here is the first talker!
I'm Umi Umbaya from Tsubaki Factory, and I'm looking forward to talking to you.
We had the Hina Festival, and we won the lottery, and we've been working with Eva Takataki-chan and Duo Duo Duo.
We won the lottery and performed as a duo with Eva Takitaki-chan and Kii Hitomi.
I wasn't sure if it was going to be OK.
Then Dambara-san came to see us.
I said I'd ask her about it.
He told me it was going to be all right, so I did my best on the day.
I was able to do my best on the day.
Thank you very much.
They're really good friends because they're in the same class.
They seemed to get on well with each other, and I got the feeling that they could say anything to each other.
You were really cool in the show.
I was a little surprised to learn that you were really nervous.
I see.
I never thought so at all.
Really?
I always thought of you as a hard-working girl, and you didn't seem nervous at all.
Eva Kim... last year...
EvaTakisaki-chan was really nervous when she won the solo at the lottery for the Hina Festival, and we all watched her nervousness last year,
This year, I was really impressed by the two of them singing happily,
I thought, 'Wow, they've grown up so much',
When I asked her about it, she said that Yumi was more nervous than her because there was someone next to her,
I was really surprised to hear that you are a nervous girl, and I was really nervous.
I usually get a stomach ache before a concert.
I usually get a stomach ache before a concert, and I'm so nervous I want to stuff myself.
But Eva was also nervous, so we were able to talk to each other and say let's do our best.
I see. But if it had been just the two of us, I think we would have been a bit more reassuring,
I was nervous at the Hina Fest, but I had a lot of fun memories, so thank you to everyone who came.
Thank you very much for coming.
Now then, let's talk about this theme this time!
We're going to talk about what we're thinking and feeling for each other, mainly about our singing performance.
I'd like to talk about one of these topics.
Let's see, what should we do?
Let's see, Rec? I'd like to talk about...
Yes, yes, I do.
Rec? Yes.
I'm interested in how other people record because I'm pretty much the only one in the booth.
I'm quite interested in how the other girls record, because I go in the booth by myself.
I'm curious about how they prepare for it.
When I first joined Juice, there were so many things I didn't understand.
I would observe my senior's leg for an hour, and then
I would observe the leg of the senior member before me for an hour and then try to do my own leg.
I used to do that for the first year or two.
It's like the way they go about the leg, or the pitch changes a bit, or something.
It happens sometimes, doesn't it?
I wanted to know about that before I started.
So I'd do my own regs after observing to reduce my anxiety as much as possible.
It's not like that now.
But rather than listening to a lot of songs and trying to imitate their singing style...
But rather than listening to a song and trying to imitate the person's singing style, once I've got the right pitch and extension, I practice karaoke in my own way.
I try to sing in my own way, to make the most of my own habits, to bring out the best of myself in a good way.
I think about what I'm going to do here to bring out the best of myself, so that's how I do it now.
I wonder how you feel about it, Fumi, because at the beginning I was observing the recording of my seniors.
I was also able to observe my seniors recording, but recently I've been a bit more anxious than I expected.
I'm a bit of a worrier than you might think, and I struggle a lot with pitch.
If I don't learn it by playing the piano, I won't be able to fix it.
I know that I have to check and work on the rhythm, which is my problem, too.
I know that I have to check the rhythm and other things that I have to work on, but first of all, I have to play the notes carefully,
I think the image of Tsubaki Factory's songs is that they are often quite sad,
I think that the songs of Tsubaki Factory are often sad songs, but I put in an edge voice and other small details later on, and then I try to make the song more expressive.
expression, thinking about how we can make the song better.
I also listen to other artists' songs to get into the world of the song.
I also listen to other artists' songs and get hints from them.
Do you listen to a lot of other songs before the REC?
When the songs from the REC, for example, I'm Not a Mistake, I Don't Cry, come in,
I listened to some of the songs of Miriya Kato, for example - ah ah ah. - I sometimes listen to them and get hints from them.
Maybe Zambara-san usually has a lot of drawers.
You have a lot of drawers.
It's precisely because I don't have enough drawers like that.
Incorporating from other sources
I'm worried that if I want to incorporate, the expression will become a bit shallow.
But I understand, I think it's really difficult to sing about love.
I understand.
I don't understand it, so I try to work with other films and songs.
So I try to understand what it's like, and then I try to bring it out.
So I only have an image of what the main character was going through in her love life, and that kind of thing.
I might do a lot of input too.
I watch a lot of live footage.
Well, it's not just the song, but also the face that changes the song.
Yes, really.
The way you open your mouth.
I saw a lot of footage of Danbara-san facing the audience, and I thought that the corners of his mouth look different depending on how he sings, so I've been paying a lot of attention to the way he changes his face.
I've been paying a lot of attention to this since about two years ago.
I don't really think about doing it this way now, but...
I don't really think about doing it this way now, but I have to make that sad face.
I can't do that kind of voice.
I sing with my face because I don't have the face for that kind of performance.
I'm not really worried about pitch and the way I open my mouth, it's not like I'm showing it off, so it's quite embarrassing.
There are times when I can't watch the recording footage myself.
I'm sure there are a lot of people who've seen it, but I'm facing the song, and it's my face when I'm only singing, so it's quite embarrassing, but... but I don't know.
I'm making a voice that includes that, so I'm saying I'm serious about it.
I'm serious about it, and I want people to enjoy the video of the leg too.
I'm...
Yes!
I'm usually in the same group as Danmaralulu, so when I look back at the footage of the show...
I can see how she sings with her face.
I can really understand how she sings with her face.
I also learn a lot from Lulu.
I'm not the type of person who thinks too much about recording.
I love recording itself very much.
It's a luxury to be able to listen to the sound purely with my ears.
I've never really listened to the members' thoughts on recording before, so it's interesting to hear them in a fresh and new way.
I wanted to know about the recording process, so I watched the footage many times on Apkami, but what happened before that was different from what each individual was doing.
I thought that was fun.
But also the way you think about the lyrics and what kind of inspiration you get from them.
I got to know how they think about the lyrics and where they get their hints from.
I also learned a lot about how they think about lyrics and what kind of sources they get their hints from.
I really liked Yumi and Ruru's songs.
I also liked their performances.
I'm glad I was able to peek inside their heads a little.
That's all for Apkami Photo Gallery.
I'm sure you'll be fine as usual.
Morning Musume。24Makino Maria and
JuiceJuice's Ria Matsunaga.
Next up.
Hello Project Hina Fest 2024 making video
Hello Project Hina Fest 2024 took place at Makuhari Messe on 30 and 31 March.
Hello Project Hina Fest 2024
We'll be focusing on the solos and the shuffle units.
Please have a look at it. me meme me
me me me
What do you think I mean by "I'm out"? Well, um, something like...
Well, stay in tune.
I'll take it one step at a time.
Yeah, yeah.
Charming.
Yeah, it's okay to have a day to yourself.
Thank God for that.
We are friends
We are ROOTSYou are blue
You are blue
Forever I never was a girl
You are blue, you are blue, you are blue, you are blue, you are blue
It's okay to be one by one
I'm thankful, I'm tense, I'm loud, I'm a friend...
Towards the clumsy one
The stars of the night are dedicated, they never rest.
First of all, what does clean mean when you put it in?
It was the first time I'd heard the word, so...
It was the first time the five of us hit it as a shuffle unit for the Hina Festivals, and my first impression was that if there were five of us, we could do anything.
I've been to Hinabesu a couple of times? And I kept missing for the first seven years or so.
And then one time I won, and then I kept winning, so...
I was like, what if this is the first time I've missed out?
So I've been working with a newcomer, like a duo.
Like an internship.
Like me and the new guy, who was called the education intern.
Oh, it's not a duo.
Five of us. But one thing I'm glad I didn't break off in my mind,
I was also interested in who the members were the most.
What about you, Hana-chan?
It's my first time to participate in Hina-japan,
I drew a prize and it turned out to be the winner, so I was really happy.
That's right.
Yes, that's right. And when I played the members, they were all there, so I felt happy.
I'm so happy.
I was absent on the day of the lottery, so Miyo played instead of me. Hina and Mio drew the lots for me. Mio Hirai drew the lottery instead of me, but Mio also won it herself, and she won it for me,
I'm glad that the owner of the strong spirit drew it for me and that I was able to get into the unit safely.
This is the third Hina Fest for me and Yagi,
I wanted to win the last two times, but I was unsuccessful for a long time,
So I feel happy that I finally won,
I don't know if I'll win again, so I'm thinking that it might be the first and last time in my life,
I'm rehearsing now.
I don't know, I'm really tight-fisted.
I was really happy.
It was my dream to cross over to the Hina Festivals unit before I joined.
You mean before you joined Hello! Project?
Yes, that's right. It would be strange to say that it was before I joined Hello! Project, it would be strange to say that it was before I joined,
Project, but when I joined, there was a shuffle unit at the Hina Festivals that I wanted to do,
I was really happy to be a part of it this time.
It's great.
Eh, I'm really anxious and nervous.
It's a mixture.
It was some kind of event at that Satoyama,
I don't know if it was the event or the booth, but the customers told me.
They said they were looking forward to it.
But I'm a bit nervous.
I had a good time at the Bi-ha event, so I'm a bit nervous,
I'm hoping I'll be able to settle down and do it.
It's important to get yourself up there,
I'm the kind of person who can't think about anything if I get too excited, so I'm going to do my best to stay calm and have fun.
There are members who are performing for the first time together, and we are all working very hard together.
It's a fun song, so I want to have a lot of fun and do my best.
It's okay to have a day when you're alone, you'll realise how much you appreciate it.
You got good friends
You got good
I don't know if I could sing the song well, but I really enjoyed the feeling of raising it in my own way, so I'm filled with a sense of accomplishment, and I'm also very proud of the five of us, Sakura Oda, Reina Yokoyama, Sayu Teguchi and Goto,
I was able to get close to all four of them, Sakura Oda, Reina Yokoyama, Sayu Teguchi and Hana Goto, and we became good friends.
We got to know each other and our bond deepened.
I felt a sense of friendship.
It was so much fun.
There were so many engines and things like that.
I said I was going to do my best.
I was so nervous when I got out of the car.
I was having a lot of fun.
There was a lot of eye contact during the songs.
I'm really sad that it's over now.
The bond between the 5 of us was so strong.
It was a super fun and memorable stage.
I think it was great.
I think the five of us felt like a great team.
We worked together until the very last minute of the show.
We worked shoulder to shoulder.
We were like helping each other out, so we were able to do it well.
I wanted Hana-chan to sing the first part of the song, so I was really happy,
Just before I sent her off, I thought it was very beneficial to leave the timing of the most nervous part of the song to one person, but she was doing her best, just as we had practised, and thanks to that we got off to a good start.
I almost cried, everyone watching. They were like mums. It was fun. The first Goto Hana was so good, I almost cried,
But after it was over, the members of Morning,
Kitagawa told us that we all looked really good earlier,
We had a lot of fun and everyone looked really good,
I think it was a success. Thank you very much.
I was also watching the show from the sleeve.
Everyone was shining in their own way.
When I saw Kotohana-chan.
I was watching over her.
She was so cute.
I was like...
The members are like the sun.
The members are so energetic.
I thought that the members who gathered here brightened up the place and the songs just by being there.
The first song started with Hana Goto.
Hana Goto herself is a bright girl like the sun.
I thought her singing voice was like the morning sun.
When I saw the sunrise, my heart was drawn in,
I think it's something that makes you look at it quietly, rather than saying, 'Wow, it's beautiful',
I got that impression from her singing voice, and I thought it was wonderful.
That's all for Hello! Project Hina Fest 2024 making-of video.
Let's spend a relaxing day today with Maria Makino.
Riae Matsunaga have sent you.
It's time to say goodbye to Apkami!
And now, once again...
We've seen a lot of footage.
I, Matsunaga, was impressed by...
was the footage of Hina festival 2024.
of Hina Fest 2024.
Until just before the show.
Sakura Oda and Hana Goto were practicing together
Sakura Oda and Hana Goto were practicing together.
I was so happy to see the behind-the-scenes of their performance.
I'm really looking forward to next year.
I, Maria Makino, am going to take part in the new section, "Apkami Photo Gallery".
I'm Maria Makino, and I'm going to be doing a new section called "Apkami Photo Gallery".
I'm glad I got to see it because I learned about Ruru Danbara and Yumi Kasai's attitude towards recording and how they prepare for it, and I thought it would be more enjoyable to watch the Apkami recording videos after I learned about that.
In Apu-Kami, we go behind the scenes of the production of the various artists belonging to the Upfront Group.
We'll introduce you to the parts you don't normally get to see, so please subscribe to our channel!
This time on UpCami
I'll be talking to Morning Musume。 24 Mariaki Makino and
JuiceJuice's Leah Matsunaga.
Goodbye.
Next time on Upokami
We'll continue with our new corner, Upokami Photo Gallery.
And
Hello Project Hina Fest 2024.
We will be revealing the back side of the story.
Enjoy!
Come on, shine.